Dear Sir or Madam

I am a hard-working and determined professional seeking an opportunity to succeed in a dynamic where I can grow. Logical and results-driven Web Developer/Digital Marketer and Graphic Designer dedicated to solving digital business objectives from small to multinational enterprises.

A Media and Journalism graduate from Nelson Mandela Bay Metropole University and a certified digital marketer from the University of Stellenbosch and Quirk digital. Over 10 years' experience in marketing and graphic design from freelance work to managing large campaigns for well- respected AD companies and video production houses. Five years ago I started my front end web developer and coding journey a continuation of my love for all things digital.

Please allow me to highlight my key skills:

- Able to effectively manage my time through careful planning and organisation of work activities
- An aptitude for identifying and resolving problems efficiently
- Excellent communication skills that result in positive interpersonal relationships
- A track record of meeting deadlines and producing accurate work of high standard
- Proven ability to make sound decisions based on valid information
- The capacity to learn and apply new information quickly and accurately
- Strong computer skills with proficiency in web design and graphic design tools as well as MS Office

I am an excellent team player who enjoys new challenges, thrives under pressure and will tenaciously approach the most complex and critical subjects. A strategist with an eye for detail, my goals and aspirations fully aligned with that of the corporation.

I am convinced that I can be an asset in any position requiring hard work, enthusiasm and reliability and I look forward to hearing from you in the near future.

The enclosed resume expands on my qualifications and experience.

Thank you for your time and consideration.

Please also have a look at my portfolio at https://www.behance.net/DonavanCalitz Sincerely,

Donavan Calitz

Enclosed is my CV for your perusal.

CURRICULUM VITAE

Donavan Calitz

Contact Details

9 Macon Road, Lorraine Port Elizabeth, South Africa

Cell: +2764 952 8080

E-mail: donavancalitz@gmail.com

Personal Profile

A Media and Journalism graduate from the Nelson Mandela Bay Metropole University and a certified digital marketer from the University of Stellenbosch and Quirk digital. Over 10-year experience in marketing and graphic design from freelance work to managing large campaigns for well-respected Ad companies and video production houses. Five years' experience in front end web development, starting with WordPress and culminating in a online degree in front end web development and intro to coding from Udacity.

Possesses good writing and communication skills, excellent problem solver and works well under pressure, having worked and studied within a deadline-based industry for over 8 years. An excellent team player who enjoys new challenges, thrives under pressure and will tenaciously approach the most complex and critical of subjects. A strategist with an eye for detail, my goals and aspirations fully aligned with that of the corporation.

Education

Journalism Graduate at Nelson Mandela Metropolitan University Majoring in Print Design

Online Degree in Front End Development and Intro to Coding from Udacity

Certified Digital Marketer through Stellenbosch University and Quirk Digital

Matriculated 2002 at Andrew Rabie High school

<u>Interests</u>

- Reading
- Writing (currently working on a comic book to be published online)
- RC Quadcopters and Drones

- RC Trucks
- PC Gaming
- Football
- Skateboarding
- Cycling

Extra information

- Published two poems in an internationally published book of poetry
- Published two short stories in an American book of short stories

Computer program training

- HTML5, CSS3
- Java Script (Limited but learning)
- C# (Limited but learning)
- Coral draw suite (11 and above)
- Adobe After Effects(CS 3 and above)
- Adobe Illustrator (CS 3 and above)
- Adobe indesign (CS 3 and above)
- Adobe Photoshop (CS 3 and above)
- Adobe Premier (CS 3 and above)
- Microsoft office
- All generic sound editing software

 Creo Spire colour workflow programs

Work Experience

May 2018-Current

HELLA South Africa Uitenhage **Digital Marketing Specialist**

- Responsible for the growing the digital footprint of HELLA South Africa
- User Experience design and optimization for International Websites
- Filming and editing of Youtube videos
- Responsible for creating Social media road map and content for all social media accounts
- Creation of Websites (WordPress and HTML/CSS) and content management of all websites
- Digitisation of tools used to help customers as well as consumers
- Creation and management of Adwords campaign
- Creation of Digital Marketing campaigns for new products and promotions
- Reporting of statistics of social media and Websites to management and the board

May 2018-January 2019

Contract Work International Digital Marketing Consultant

- Created and managed two accounts for an International and National Company
- Designed and created e-commerce store
- Created and Managed digital marketing campaigns
- Create digital mailer campaigns
- Managed AdWords Campaigns
- Audit and implement changes to SEO of company websites to drive more leads

October 2015-Present

Bikegear.co.za Port Elizabeth **Digital Marketing Manager**

- Manager of the Digital Marketing Department
- Designer and Webmaster of the Bikegear.co.za website and E-Commerce platform
- Responsible for all digital marketing campaigns
- Liaising with print media department to create targeted marketing campaigns
- Managing social media updates
- Copywriting material for digital marketing campaigns including e-mail campaigns and online advertising.

June 2012-October 2015

Adhoc Productions Port Elizabeth Motion Graphics /

Videographer

- Handled all Graphic Design and corporate identities
- Motion Graphic Artists doing work for clients such as Wildsfees and creating ads for television
- Was credited on E-tv for a documentary called "Ma se Kind" where I handled the Motion Graphics and special effects.

September 2011-June 2012

TD Consulting/Rockstar Media Port Elizabeth Art Director/ Videographer University Worked mainly as a videographer and editor, specialising in special effect and video graphics

- Created various intros and TV Spots for Bay TV
- Conceptualised and shot and edited music videos of local artists
- Shot and edited various weddings and corporate events

December 2009-September 2011

Speedprint and Copy Port Elizabeth Manager/ Art Director

- Head Designer
- Manager of the 3 graphic designers, disrupting tasks and quality control

June 2008-June 2009

Wildmoon Studios Port Elizabeth Graphic Artist

- Designer of various ad campaigns, print projects, Logos and company profiles
- Conceptualising company look and feels and advertising and marketing campaigns for both large and small companies
- Worked with an extremely quick turn over time, gaining valuable experience in doing quick designs yet still maintaining the best quality
- The quality standards are extremely high, thus I have learned to push my own designs to the ultimate limit

July 2007- June 2008

Stormsky Advertising Port Elizabeth Print Manager

- Designer of various ad campaigns, print projects, Logos and company profiles
- Manager of the Print Department, instructing staff and managing printing consumables and machine operations
- Gained good experience working with some of the biggest brands in South Africa, including Billabong and VW motor corporation

References are available on request